Stephan Iskander

github.com/stephan543 in linkedin.com/in/stephaniskander

🛂 stephan.iskander@gmail.com 📞 416-826-5287

Toronto · Canada

A formally trained engineer gone to the tech-side, with a deep curiosity for creating web tools that save time, money, energy and effort. Proven experience building web apps and executing successful personal and professional projects.

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

Environmental Engineering 2014 - 2019

GPA - 81.83%

HARD - SKILLS

Languages:

JavaScript, PHP, HTML5, CSS

Frameworks:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS **Workflow:**

Git, Bash, VS Code

SOFT - SKILLS

Oral and Written Communication
Patience · Time Management
Organized · Focused · Consistent
Self-Motivated · Honest · Joyful
Patient · Trainable · Adaptable

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Humber College (CST Team)

Jan 2021 - Present

Technical Producer

Toronto, CA

- Tasked with implementing 3 virtual classroom software platforms in order to support groups of 10-40 people.
- Saved 1/3rd of budgeted training time, by independently learning how to implement, troubleshoot and teach the software platforms.
- Excelled in a client facing role, receiving high quality engagement feedback scores from all client sessions.

Pinchin Ltd. (ERC Group)

June 2019 - Nov 2019

Environmental Project Engineering Intern

Mississauga, CA

- Independently managed portfolios of storm assessments; client communications and predictive model calculations (Excel VBA scripts).
- Assisted in the project management of storm and waste water solutions; pricing, design, on-site supervision and client satisfaction.
- Delivered thorough documentation for municipalities (Engineering Evaluation Reports and Environmental Compliance Approvals) reviewed by multiple licensed professional engineers.

Nissan Canada Finance

Jul 2016 - Sep 2016

Marketing Co-op — NCESI

Toronto, CA

- Assisted in the project management and migration of a new web-based contract registration system.
- Performed data analysis and reported development for management, resulting in a backlog of 10 000 emails to be reduced to 5 000 within 3 months.
- Ad hoc tasks/projects as required by department manager.

PROJECTS

Time Picker (1)

- A Web App that calls the Google Calendar API and creates free time slots for clients/colleagues.
- Implemented a recursive algorithm that creates an array of free time slots from given meetings.
- Used: ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB

Stephanlskander.org 3

- A site that stores my recipes inside JSON files and calculates any client-side changes to proportions.
- Used PHP to load new recipes from database and to handle form validation.
- Used: PHP. JS. HTML5. CSS

Full Stack Library System Ω

- This project is a full-stack application that is able to store and relate book information, including: Genres, Authors, Rental Status and Inventories.
- Once deployed the site will allow users to perform CRUD operations on all book instances.
- Used: NodeJS, ExpressJS, NPM, MongoDB, Mongo Atlas and Microsoft Azure.